Guide to the Alfred Schütz Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1925-1958; Series I; 5.75; (14 boxes)
  - Language, Language Disturbances, and the Texture of Mind
    - Drafts, typescript carbon, corrected (with carbon of letter from Schütz to Felicia Johnson Deyrup, 1950 Jan 10) [6341-6378] (Box 11, Folder 189)
  - In Memory of Felix Kaufmann
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 190)
    - Draft, holograph, [6379-6393], 1949 Dec 31 (Box 11, Folder 191)
    - Draft, typescript [6394-6403], n.d. (Box 11, Folder 192)
    - Draft, typescript corrected, with setting typescript, 1949 Dec 31 (Box 11, Folder 193)
    - Short draft, typescript [6404-6412], n.d. (Box 11, Folder 194)
    - Letters from Else Kaufmann and Social Research, holograph and typescript [6413-6416] (Box 11, Folder 195)
  - Besprechung von M. Farber: The Foundation of Phenomenology
    - Draft, holograph [6417-6426], n.d. (Box 11, Folder 196)
    - Draft, typescript [6427-6430], n.d. (Box 11, Folder 197)
    - Letters (Schütz to Marvin Farber and Eric Voegelin to Schütz), typescript [6431-6433] (Box 11, Folder 198)
  - Some Leading Concepts of Phenomenology
    - Draft, holograph, [6434-6464], 1943 Jul (Box 11, Folder 199)
    - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected [6465-6488], n.d. (Box 11, Folder 200)
    - Draft fragments, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1943 Jul 21 (Box 11, Folder 201)
  - Edmund Husserl's "Ideas III"
    - Draft, holograph, [6489-6509], 1952 Nov (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - Draft, typescript [6510-6524], n.d. (Box 11, Folder 203)
  - Phänomenologie und Kulturwissenschaft
    - Notes, holograph, [6525-6528], 1939 Jan (Box 11, Folder 204)
    - Draft, typescript [6529-6533], n.d. (Box 11, Folder 205)
    - New draft, typescript, corrected [6534-6565], 1939 Aug 8 (Box 11, Folder 206)
    - New draft, typescript carbon, corrected, [6534-6565], 1939 Aug 8 (Box 11, Folder 207)
    - English translation by R. H. Williams, typescript [6566-6584], n.d. (Box 11, Folder 208)
    - Letter from Schütz to R. H. Williams, typescript [6585-6588], n.d. (Box 11, Folder 209)
  - Lebensformen und Sinnstrucktur
    - Draft, typescript carbon, [6589-6756] (Box 11, Folder 210)
  - Besprechung zu Otaka's Buch: Lehre vom sozialen Verband
    - Draft, holograph [6757-6777], n.d. (Box 11, Folder 211)
  - Das Problem der Relevanz
    - Early notes, holograph, [6778-6787], 1929 (Box 11, Folder 212)
  - Exzerpte und Notizen zu M. Weber: Wissenschaftslehre (1921)
    - Contents include: Johs. v. Kries: Logik Werner[?] Sombart: Die Juden und das Wirtschaftsleben Georg[?] Simmel: Geschichtsphilosophie Max Weber: Protestantische Ethik Emile Durkheim: Regeln Speech notes with Winternitz and Eric Voegelin, holograph [6788-6826] (Box 11, Folder 213)
  - Recollections of Husserl and of Husserl's Influence on Me
    - Draft, typescript [6827-6836], n.d. (Box 11, Folder 214)
  - Sinn einer Kunstform (Musik)
    - Drafts, typescript, corrected [6837-6875], n.d. (Box 12, Folder 215)
  - Fragments on the Phenomenology of Music
    - Draft, holograph, [6876-6941], 1944 Jul (Box 12, Folder 216)
    - Mimeograph version [6942-7007], n.d. (Box 12, Folder 217-218)
    - Preface to mimeograph version by Fred Kersten, typescript [7008-7035], n.d. (Box 12, Folder 219)
  - Über den Witz
    - Draft notes and excerpts, holograph, [7036-7053] (Box 12, Folder 220)
  - Fragments of "Paradoxien der Phänomenologie" by Eugen Fink, 1937
    - Draft (English), holograph, [7054-7059], n.d. (Box 12, Folder 221)
  - Das Problem der Personalität in der Sozialwelt
    - First draft, holograph, [7060-7101], 1936 Jul-Aug (Box 12, Folder 222)
    - Fragments of the first principal part (1936 Jul. 28)
      - Die Einheit des Leibes, draft, holograph [7102-7133], 1937 Jul 31 (Box 12, Folder 223)
      - Die Tempora des Ich, draft, holograph, [7134-7158], 1937 Aug 13 (Box 12, Folder 224)
      - Die Konstitution der Wirkwelt und ihrer Modifikationen, draft, holograph [7159-7188], 1937 Aug 25 (Box 12, Folder 225)
      - Die Welt des Traumes, draft, holograph, [7189-7211], 1937 Aug 26-27 (Box 12, Folder 226)
  - Unterschlungen über Grundbegriffe und Methoden der Socialwissenschaften
    - Draft, holograph, [7212-7230], n.d. (Box 12, Folder 227)
  - Sinnstruktur der Novelle: Goethe
    - Draft, typescript with holograph corrections [7231-7274 and unnumbered duplicate pages] (Box 12, Folder 228)
  - Wilhelm Meisters Lehrjahre
    - Draft, holograph, [7275-7306], 1948 Jun 6 (Box 12, Folder 229)
    - Draft, typescript, corrected [7307-7333], n.d. (Box 12, Folder 230)
    - Letter from Schütz to Social Research, typescript [7334], 1952 Feb 29 (Box 12, Folder 231)
  - Zur Nationalökonomie
    - Draft, holograph [7335-7341], n.d. (Box 12, Folder 232)
  - Spracharbeit
    - Draft, holograph, [7342-7380], 1925 Jul 15 (Box 13, Folder 233)
    - Draft, typescript (beginning with page 39, with notes from 1925-1927) [7381-7397], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 234)
  - Reviews
    - Alfred Schütz on Formale und transzendentale Logik by Edmund Husserl, printed version, Deutsche Literaturzeitung, [7398-7403], 1933 Apr (Box 13, Folder 235)
    - Alfred Schütz on Meditation cartésiennes by Edmund Husserl, printed version, Deutsche Literaturzeitung, [7404-4710], 1932 Dec 18 (Box 13, Folder 236)
    - Alfred Schütz on Grundprobleme der Nationalökonomie, by Ludwig von Mises, printed version, Deutsche Literaturzeitung [7411-7414], 1934 Jan 7 (Box 13, Folder 237)
    - Felix Kaufmann on Der Sinnhafte Aufbau... by Alfred Schütz, printed version, Deutsche Literaturzeitung, [7415-7417], 1932 Sep 4 (Box 13, Folder 238)
    - Franz Borkenau on Der Sinnhafte Aufbau... by Alfred Schütz draft, typescript [7418-7419], 1932 (Box 13, Folder 239)
    - Alfred Schütz on Cartesianische Meditationen by Edmund Husserl, draft (English), holograph, [7420-7426] (Box 13, Folder 240)
  - Husserl's Importance for the Social Sciences
    - Draft, holograph [7427-7461], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 241)
    - Draft, typescript [7462-7477], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 242)
  - T. S. Eliot's Concept of Culture
    - Draft, holograph [7478-7515], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 243)
    - Letters in reference to the publication, dated between the years 1950-52, holograph and typescript [7516-7526] (Box 13, Folder 244)
    - Draft, typescript [11116-11142], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 245)
    - Drafts, typescript carbon, corrected, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 246)
  - Type and Eidos
    - Draft, typescript [7527-7555], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 247)
    - Draft, holograph [10287-10341], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 248)
    - Earlier draft, holograph [10374-10418], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 249)
    - First draft, holograph [10419-10433], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 250)
    - Studien zum Typusbegriff, holograph [10434-10526], 1953 (Box 13, Folder 251-252)
  - Comments on the Meeting on Equality
    - Draft, typescript, [7556-7560], 1955 (Box 13, Folder 253)
  - Memoranda on the Graduate Faculty of the New School for Social Research
    - Letter from Schütz to Hans Staudinger, [7561-7565], 1956 Feb 23 (Box 14, Folder 254)
    - The Graduate School Today and Tomorrow, draft, typescript [7566-7567] (Box 14, Folder 255)
    - The Scope and Function of a Department of Philosophy within the Graduate Faculty, draft, typescript [7568-7583] (Box 14, Folder 256)
    - The Graduate Faculty's own Function within the New School, draft, typescript [7584-7590], n.d. (Box 14, Folder 257)
    - Letter from Schütz to Albert Solomon [7591-7593], 1947 May 23 (Box 14, Folder 258)
  - Einleitung zur Bearbeitung der Husserl-Manuskripte (Phänomenologie des Raumes)
    - Draft (English), holograph, [7594-7598], n.d. (Box 14, Folder 259)
    - Draft, typescript [7599-7603], n.d. (Box 14, Folder 260)
    - Letter from Felix Kaufmann to Marvin Farber and draft of leter from Schütz to Kaufmann [7604-7608], 1940 Jul 22 (Box 14, Folder 261)
  - Hic Egregie Progressus Sum
    - Draft (German), holograph [11143-11150], 1958 Dec 7 (Box 14, Folder 262)
    - English translation by Helmut R. Wagner, draft, typescript [11151-11159], n.d. (Box 14, Folder 263)
  - The Problem of Social Reality
    - Draft, holograph [11160-11162], n.d. (Box 14, Folder 264)
    - The Meaning Structure of the Social World, draft, typescript [11163-11164], n.d. (Box 14, Folder 265)
    - Exemplar from The Problem of Social Reality, complete draft, typescript [11165-11168], n.d. (Box 14, Folder 266)
  - Miscellaneous unnumbered manuscripts
    - "Leitsätze zur Diskussion über meinen Vortrag vom 22 Mai 1930 vorbereitet für den Seminarabend am 27 Juni 1930", draft typescript carbon (Box 14, Folder 267)
    - [Memoir of Kurt Reizler] (written with Horace Kallen), drafts, typescript carbon, corrected and mimeograph (with letters from Horace Kallen, n.d.), 1955 (Box 14, Folder 268)
    - Notes and manuscript fragments on various topics, ca. 1928-55 (Box 14, Folder 269-270)
    - Notes on music, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 271)
    - Open letter, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 272)
    - "Phenomenology and Social Sciences," notes and draft, typescript carbon (Box 14, Folder 273)
    - [Positivism and Social Science], draft, typescript carbon (Box 14, Folder 274)
    - "Reply to Professor Morris' Comment on My Paper," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 275)
    - Review of Marvin Farber's Foundations of Phenomenology (of 1943), draft, holograph (Box 14, Folder 276)
    - "The Social World and the Theory of Social Action," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 277)
    - "Some Equivocations on the Notion of Responsibility," draft, holograph (with draft of letter to Sidney Hook, 1957 Mar 22) (Box 14, Folder 278)
    - "Tomoo Otakas Grundlegende der Lehre vom sozialen," printed version (photocopy), Zeitschrift für Öffentliches Recht with English translation by Fred Kersten, typescript carbon (Box 14, Folder 279)
    - Edition [translation?] of Husserl's "Grundlegende Untersuchungen zum phänomenologischen Ursprung der Räumlichkeit der Natur," draft, typescript carbon, corrected (Box 14, Folder 280)
    - Edition [translation?] of Husserl's "Die Welt der lebendigen Gegenwart und die Konstitution der ausserliebchen Umwelt," draft, holograph, corrected, 1944 Jan 1 (Box 14, Folder 281)
    - Edition [translation?] of Husserl's "Zur Konstitution der Tastwelt - Die haptischen Kinaesthesen," draft, typescript, corrected (Box 14, Folder 282)
    - "Über Wissen und Wirtschaft," draft, typescript carbon (with notes by Helmut Wagner, 1979) (Box 14, Folder 283)
    - Untitled paper, outline and notes, holograph photocopy (Box 14, Folder 284)
- Teaching and Research Materials, 1940-1959; Series II; 2.25; (5 boxes)
  - Lecture and Course materials
    - The Theory of Social Role, Spring Term 1956, [7609-7711 and unnumbered] (Box 15, Folder 285-288)
    - The Theory of the Social Group, Spring Term 1954, [7775-8050 and unnumbered] (Box 15, Folder 289-295)
    - Theory of Social Action, 1954 [8051-8205 and unnumbered] (Box 15, Folder 296-299)
    - Other Minds, Spring Term 1957, [8206-8648 and unnumbered] (Box 16, Folder 300-308)
    - Causality, Spring Term 1958, [8649-9085 and unnumbered] (Box 16, Folder 309-314)
    - Causality, Spring Term 1958, [8649-9085 and unnumbered] (Box 17, Folder 315-318)
    - Symbolic Logic, [9086-9172], [1940?] (Box 17, Folder 319-320)
    - Sign and Symbol I, [9173-9326 and unnumbered] (Box 17, Folder 321-324)
    - Sign and Symbol II, [9327-9546] (Box 17, Folder 325-328)
    - Self and Society, Fall Term 1951, 1957, [9547-9824 and unnumbered] (Box 17, Folder 329-334)
    - Equality, Prejudice, and Discrimination, Fall Term 1956 [9825-9935] (Box 18, Folder 335-336)
    - Methodology of the Social Sciences, Spring Term 1951, 1952, Fall Term 1956, [9936-10134 and unnumbered], 1951-56 (Box 18, Folder 337-341)
    - The Stranger, [10135-10286], n.d. (Box 18, Folder 342-344)
    - Methodology (combined seminar with Löwe) (includes letters: Fritz Machlup to Schütz, 1949 Nov 8, Edwin M. Schur to Schütz, n.d. and Robert Heilbroner to Schütz, n.d.), [10342-10373] (Box 18, Folder 345)
    - Sociology of Language (includes holograph and typescript, photocopy notes by H. R. Wagner), [10527-10555 and unnumbered], 1952 (Box 18, Folder 346-347)
    - Introduction to the Theory of Sociology, Spring Term 1943, [10556-10610] (Box 18, Folder 348)
    - Contemporary European Philosophy, [10611-10802 and unnumbered], 1956[?] (Box 18, Folder 349-353)
    - Bergson/James, [10803-11044 and unnumbered], 1958 (Box 19, Folder 354-359)
    - Sociology of Sciences, [11045-11068], n.d. (Box 19, Folder 360)
    - Supreme Court Decisions, [11069-11115], n.d. (Box 19, Folder 361)
    - Man and His Tools: Theory of Technical Progress, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 362)
    - Problems of a Sociology of Knowledge (includes notes by Helmut Wagner), 1945, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 363)
    - Situation of Everyday Life and Current Events in the Light of Sociological Theory (Box 19, Folder 364)
    - Studies in Applied Theory, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 365)
    - The Problem of Social Reality, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 366)
  - Reading notes
    - Aristotle, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 367)
    - Henri Bergson, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 368)
    - Walter Biemel's article on Husserl's Encyclopedia Britannica article, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 369)
    - Dorion Cairn's conversations with Husserl and Fink (Box 19, Folder 370)
    - Alois Dempf, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 371)
    - William Hammerschmidt on Whitehead, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 372)
    - Homer, Odyssey, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 372a)
    - Edmund Husserl on Intersubjectivity (Box 19, Folder 373)
    - Edmund Husserl's Formale and Tranzendentale Logik, 1932, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 374)
    - Edmund Husserl's Krisis (Box 19, Folder 375)
    - Edmund Husserl's Manuscript B I 15 I-IV (Box 19, Folder 376)
    - Edmund Husserl's Manuscript B I 16 (Box 19, Folder 377)
    - Edmund Husserl's Manuscripts (various) (Box 19, Folder 378)
    - Edmund Husserl's Vorlesungen zur Phänomenologie des innere Zeitbewustseins (Box 19, Folder 379)
    - Leibniz and others (Box 19, Folder 380)
    - Marx, Werner, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 381)
    - J. S. Mill's Utilitarianism, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 382)
    - Bertrand Russell's Our Knowledge of the External World (Box 19, Folder 383)
    - Max Scheler, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 384)
    - Jean Wahl on Descartes and Bergson (Box 19, Folder 385)
- Subject Files and Correspondence, 1927-1979; Series III; 6; (14 boxes)
  - Finding aid
    - "Keys to the Lists of the Correspondence of Alfred Schütz with a number of Friends and Scholars" by Helmut Wagner (for Herbert Spiegelberg, Eric Voegelin, Felix Kaufmann and Aron Gurwitsch), 1975 Jun (Box 20, Folder 386)
  - Abel, Reuben
    - Correspondence, 1954-58 (Box 20, Folder 387)
  - Adorno, Theodor
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 20, Folder 388)
  - Allen, Robert Loring
    - Correspondence (letter and vita from Joachim O. Ronall sent to Allen), 1958 Feb 15 (Box 20, Folder 389)
  - Allport, Gordon
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 20, Folder 390)
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science
    - Correspondence, 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 391)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science
    - Convention materials, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 392)
    - Correspondence, 1941-44 (Box 20, Folder 392)
  - American Council of Learned Societies
    - Summary of activities, 1940 (Box 20, Folder 393)
  - American Defense - Harvard Group
    - Correspondence, 1940-44 (Box 20, Folder 394)
  - American Journal of Sociology
    - Correspondence, 1943-45 (Box 20, Folder 395)
  - American Musicological Society
    - Correspondence, 1956 Mar (Box 20, Folder 396)
  - American Philosophical Association
    - Convention materials, 1940-56 (Box 20, Folder 397)
    - Correspondence, 1940-58 (Box 20, Folder 398)
    - Eastern Division on Exiled Scholars - Inventory of Personnel, 1942 Apr (Box 20, Folder 399)
  - American Sociological Society
    - Meeting program, 1941 Dec (Box 20, Folder 400)
  - Anshen, Ruth Nanda
    - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 401)
  - Antz, Louise
    - Correspondence, 1950-59, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 402)
  - Arnheim, Rudolf
    - Correspondence, 1951 Dec 7 (Box 20, Folder 403)
  - Aron, Raymond and Suzanne
    - Correspondence, 1940-59 (Box 20, Folder 404)
  - Asch, Solomon[?] E.
    - Correspondence, 1944 Dec 8 (Box 20, Folder 405)
  - Atomic Bomb
    - Clippings, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 406)
  - Aubrey, Henry G.
    - Correspondence, 1957 Jul 2 (Box 20, Folder 407)
  - Aufricht, Hans
    - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 408)
  - Beaufils, Marcel
    - Correspondence, 1946-51 (Box 20, Folder 409)
  - Beck, Lewis
    - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 410)
  - Beckett, Howard
    - Correspondence, 1951-59 (Box 20, Folder 411)
  - Bennett, John C.
    - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 412)
  - Berger, Gaston
    - Correspondence, 1947-59 (Box 20, Folder 413)
  - Berger, Peter
    - Correspondence, 1957 Nov 3 (Box 20, Folder 414)
  - Biemel, Walter
    - Correspondence, 1947-58 (Box 20, Folder 415)
  - Bien, Bettina
    - Correspondence, 1958-59 (Box 20, Folder 416)
  - Bittner, Egon
    - Correspondence, 1958 Nov 22 (Box 20, Folder 417)
  - Black, Max
    - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 418)
  - Bloomfield, L. M.
    - Clipping, 1948 Jan 24 (Box 20, Folder 419)
    - Correspondence, 1957 Jul 19 (Box 20, Folder 420)
  - Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System
    - Correspondence, 1943 Apr (Box 20, Folder 421)
  - Böhm, Rudolf
    - Correspondence, 1957-59 (Box 20, Folder 422)
  - Bonniwell, Bernard
    - Letter to Ilse Schütz, 1977 Jun 4 (Box 20, Folder 423)
  - Book catalogs
    - Catalogs, 1960, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 424)
  - Book orders
    - Order letters and receipts for books, 1950-59 (Box 20, Folder 425)
  - Brecht, Arnold
    - Correspondence, 1956, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 426)
  - Breda, H. L. van
    - Correspondence, 1946-58 (Box 20, Folder 427-430)
      Includes copies of letters from Marvin Farber and Dorion Cairns
  - Breton, Stanislaus
    - Correspondence, 1958, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 431)
  - Briefs, Goetz
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 20, Folder 432)
  - Brin, Orville G., Jr.
    - Correspondence, 1959 Jul 17 (Box 20, Folder 433)
  - Broderson, Arvid
    - Correspondence, 1951-59 (Box 20, Folder 434)
  - Brügel, Fritz
    - Clipping - obituary, 1955 Jul 8 (Box 20, Folder 435)
  - Brunner, G. S.
    - Correspondence, 1952 Mar 21 (Box 20, Folder 436)
  - Bryson, Lyman
    - Correspondence, 1954 Nov 1 (Box 20, Folder 437)
  - Buchanan, Emerson
    - Correspondence, 1953-58 (Box 20, Folder 438)
  - Burke, Kenneth
    - Correspondence, 1952-59 (Box 20, Folder 439)
  - Burshtyn, Hyman
    - Correspondence, 1952 Oct 22 (Box 20, Folder 440)
  - Cairns, Dorion
    See also: Bread, H. L. van, Box 20, folders 427-430
    - Correspondence, 1940-57 (Box 20, Folder 441)
    - Review of Aron Gurwitsch's The Field of Consciousness, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 442)
  - Callahan, W. R.
    - Correspondence, 1949 Dec 9 (Box 21, Folder 443)
  - Casanova, Jean-Claude
    - Letter to Arvid Broderson, 1960 Sep 12 (Box 21, Folder 444)
  - Charneco, Miguel
    - Correspondence, 1957 Jul 27 (Box 21, Folder 445)
  - Child, Arthur
    - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 446)
  - Cicourel, Aaron
    - Mailing address, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 447)
  - Clarke, John J.
    - "The Payments System: Problems, Fantasies, and Realities," printed version (Box 21, Folder 448)
  - Clippings
    - Miscellaneous subjects including: Blindness, Albert Einstein, T.S. Eliot, Physics and George Santayana (Box 21, Folder 449)
  - Cohen, Louis H.
    - Correspondence, 1944 Jan 8 (Box 21, Folder 450)
  - Colloque philosophique de Royaumont
    See also: Series I, Troisième Colloque Philosophique de Royaumont, Box 5, folder 76
    - Correspondence, 1957-58 (Box 21, Folder 451)
    - Meeting materials, 1957 Apr (Box 21, Folder 452)
    - Paper by Alfred Schütz, "Das Problem der Transzendentalen Intersubjektivitaet bei Husserl," typescript, carbon with French translation, 1957 Apr (Box 21, Folder 453)
    - Photograph of Schütz with Jean Wahl, Eugen Fink and Roman Ingarden in Le Figaro Litteraire, 1957 Apr 27 (Box 21, Folder 454)
  - Commons, John R.
    - "Landwirtschaftliche Breife und Goldwert," offprint (Box 21, Folder 455)
  - Conference on Methods in Philosophy and the Sciences
    - Invitation, 1941 Apr (Box 21, Folder 456)
  - Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion
    - Correspondence, 1952-57 (Box 21, Folder 457-459)
    - 1951 Conference
      - Program, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 460)
    - 1954 Conference
      - Clipping, 1954 Sep (Box 21, Folder 461)
      - Comments by Charles Morris on a paper by Alfred Schütz, with report to Morris from Schütz, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 462)
      - Program drafts and participant lists, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 463)
    - 1955 Meeting of the Fellows
      - Program drafts, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 464)
      - Reports, 1955 Aug-Sep (Box 21, Folder 465-466)
      - Paper by Alfred Schütz: "Equality and the Meaning Structure of the Social World," mimeograph, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 467)
      - Papers by others, mimeograph, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 468-481)
      - Comment on the meeting by Alfred Schütz, "In Search of the Middle Ground," drafts, holograph and typescript, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 482)
      - Comments on the meeting by others, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 483)
      - List of papers and associates, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 484)
      - Clippings, 1955 Aug (Box 22, Folder 485)
    - 1956 Preconference Meeting
      - Report, 1956 Apr (Box 22, Folder 486)
    - 1956 Institute on Ethics
      - Participant materials, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 487)
      - Committee reports, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 488-493)
      - Committee memos, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 494)
      - Memo by Alfred Schütz, "Some Considerations in Thinking of Terms of Barriers," drafts, holograph, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 495)
      - Memo by Alfred Schütz, "Some Points to be Considered in Connection with Area #2," holograph, typescript and carbon, 1956 Jun (Box 23, Folder 496)
    - 1956 Conference
      - Program drafts, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 497)
      - List of participants, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 498)
      - Registration packet (with copies of reports and notes by Alfred Schütz), 1956 (Box 23, Folder 499)
  - Congreso Nacional de Filosofia
    - Correspondence, 1948-58 (Box 23, Folder 500)
  - Coser, Lewis A.
    - Correspondence, 1953, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 501)
  - Dalton, Melville
    - Correspondence, 1956 Feb 27 (Box 23, Folder 502)
  - Deyrup, Felicia Johnson
    See also: Series I, Language, Language Disturbances and the Texture of Mind, Box 11, folder 188
    - Correspondence, 1951 Dec 7 (Box 23, Folder 503)
  - Dobsevage, Alvin
    - Correspondence, 1954 Feb 3 (Box 23, Folder 504)
  - Dworetesky, Esther
    - Correspondence, 1955 Mar 29 (Box 23, Folder 505)
  - Echavarría, José Medina
    - Correspondence, 1944 Jun 29 (Box 23, Folder 506)
  - Editions d'art Lucien Mazenod
    - Correspondence, 1955-57 (Box 23, Folder 507)
  - Editions de Minuit
    - Correspondence, 1958 Oct 23 (Box 23, Folder 508)
  - Eidelberg, Ludwig
    - Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 509)
  - Efron, Walter
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 510)
  - Ellegood, Donald R.
    - Correspondence, 1955 Apr 22 (Box 23, Folder 511)
  - Elliot, Charles
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 512)
  - Embree, Lester
    - Letter to Ilse Schütz
      See: Series I, On Multiple Realities, Box 3, folder 56
  - Encyclopedia Britannica
    - Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 513)
  - Eucken, W.
    - Correspondence, 1949 Oct 5 (Box 23, Folder 514)
      Includes photograph print of Edmund Husserl: sketch and on deathbed
  - Farber, Marvin
    See also: Series I, Besprechung von M. Farber, Box 11, folder 196
    - Correspondence, 1939-59 (Box 24, Folder 515-528)
    - Letters to Ilse Schütz, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 529)
  - Ferand, Ernest